<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Nancy Ko]]></title>
  <link href="http://nancyko.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nancyko.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-22T15:49:29-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://nancyko.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nancyko]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keeping Track]]></title>
    <link href="http://nancyko.github.io/blog/2015/08/20/keeping-track/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-20T00:28:32-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://nancyko.github.io/blog/2015/08/20/keeping-track</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Trying to learn something can be challenging.  You might not get everything at first, and have to move on to a new topic before ever feeling comfortable with the previous one. I never liked that feeling and always felt like I&rsquo;ll forget to go back to it later.</p>

<p>A lot of people say, if you don&rsquo;t want to forget something to write it down. So making a list of every topic and learning objective to keep track of everything makes sense to me. I went through a few versions because it was challenging to make just a list for a high-impact learning enivornment. Learning something conceptually and then taking those concepts and applying them in a real-world environment, the list should reflect both conceptual and applied learning to be complete. I also wanted it to be more visual where I could get a sense of where I am at a glance.</p>

<p>To make my list I started off with looking at each section of the curriculum and matching the name of the section with a column in my list and calling it &lsquo;Topic&rsquo;.  Writing the specific learning objectives in the next column followed by whether it is the conceptual or the applied part of high-impact learning. And finlly, a column that acts as my marker of whether something is complete or can I do this and green and red fields just to make it more visual.</p>

<p>After some tweaks and suggestions from others, here&rsquo;s what I came up with so far:</p>

<p>Conceptual:
<a href="http://imgur.com/zxdv9Me"><img src="http://i.imgur.com/zxdv9Me.png" title="source: imgur.com" /></a>
</br>
</br>
</br>
</br>
</br>
The applied learning objectives ask for something to be done
Applied:
<a href="http://imgur.com/M73vpR2"><img src="http://i.imgur.com/M73vpR2.png" title="source: imgur.com" /></a>
</br>
</br>
</br>
</br>
</br></p>

<p>When making my tracker, I like to have the &lsquo;Can I do this&rsquo;, &lsquo;Is this complete&rsquo; column start off with &lsquo;No&rsquo; because it feels really good when changing it to &lsquo;Yes&rsquo;.
</br>
</br>
</br>
</br>
</br>
</br>
<a href=")http://imgur.com/XlnAAjp"><img src="http://i.imgur.com/XlnAAjp.png" title="source: imgur.com" /></a>
</br>
</br>
</br>
</br>
</br>
</br>
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/q5XJKpl.png" alt="image" /></p>

<p></br>
</br>
</br>
</br>
</br></p>

<p>keep learning!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My First Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://nancyko.github.io/blog/2015/08/05/my-first-post/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-05T21:10:21-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://nancyko.github.io/blog/2015/08/05/my-first-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>End of week 2 at Flatiron School. Feeling very exhausted and overwhelmed with the amount of information and at the same time trying my hardest to absorb it all.
For me, I feel as though there is so much to do in very short amount of time. So when heard we&rsquo;re starting code reviews I was super excited. I didn&rsquo;t know what a code review was but could get a general sense.</p>

<p>So, what is a code review?  Wikipedia&rsquo;s definition is &ldquo;a systematic examination of computer source code. It is intended to find and fix mistakes overlooked in the initial development phase, improving both the overall quality of software and the developers' skills.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Turns out, there are different types of code reviews, not every company practices code reviews and those that do, may have their own take on a code review.  Code review in some cases could just be a &lsquo;chicken sexer&rsquo;, a person (or bot) that gives the final okay before the source code you&rsquo;ve written goes to the interwebs.</p>

<p>But one type that really caught my attention is peer review.</p>

<p>Peer code review: This type of code review is usually done with at least one of your colleagues. Knowledge sharing. Allows other team members to be familiar with a part of the source code they did not work on. Another set of eyes allows for fewer mistakes. Ask probing questions that start a discussion and not questions that give defensive responses.</p>

<p>GOOD: HAVE YOU CONSIDERED? HAVE YOU TRIED?
BAD: WHY DIDN&rsquo;T YOU?</p>

<p>Over time you may start to see you write more reviewable code, think more about your decisions of doing something one way as opposed to another way.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
