<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Flatiron&nbsp;school | Nancy Ko]]></title>
  <link href="http://nancyko.github.io/blog/categories/flatiron-school/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nancyko.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-09-03T07:59:05-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://nancyko.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nancyko]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My First Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://nancyko.github.io/blog/2015/08/05/my-first-post/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-05T21:10:21-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://nancyko.github.io/blog/2015/08/05/my-first-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>End of week 2 at Flatiron School. Feeling very exhausted and overwhelmed with the amount of information and at the same time trying my hardest to absorb it all.
For me, I feel as though there is so much to do in very short amount of time. So when heard we&rsquo;re starting code reviews I was super excited. I didn&rsquo;t know what a code review was but could get a general sense.</p>

<p>So, what is a code review?  Wikipedia&rsquo;s definition is &ldquo;a systematic examination of computer source code. It is intended to find and fix mistakes overlooked in the initial development phase, improving both the overall quality of software and the developers' skills.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Turns out, there are different types of code reviews, not every company practices code reviews and those that do, may have their own take on a code review.  Code review in some cases could just be a &lsquo;chicken sexer&rsquo;, a person (or bot) that gives the final okay before the source code you&rsquo;ve written goes to the interwebs.</p>

<p>But one type that really caught my attention is peer review.</p>

<p>Peer code review: This type of code review is usually done with at least one of your colleagues. Knowledge sharing. Allows other team members to be familiar with a part of the source code they did not work on. Another set of eyes allows for fewer mistakes. Ask probing questions that start a discussion and not questions that give defensive responses.</p>

<p>GOOD: HAVE YOU CONSIDERED? HAVE YOU TRIED?
BAD: WHY DIDN&rsquo;T YOU?</p>

<p>Over time you may start to see you write more reviewable code, think more about your decisions of doing something one way as opposed to another way.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
